（カイト）ちっ！
落ちたら　タダじゃ済まねえぜ。
It wouldn't be fun to fall from here.
You've built quite the dangerous puzzle here, Gammon the Galileo!
ずいぶん危険なパズルを
作ってくれるじゃねえか！
なあ！　ガリレオのギャモンよ！
（ギャモン）ハッ　ハッ！
楽しんでもらえて　何よりだ。
I'm glad you're enjoying it.
腕に　よりをかけて作った
かいがあるってもんだぜ。
It was worth the effort I put into making it then.
As a Giver of the POG!
ＰＯＧのギヴァーとしてはなぁ！
身も心も　ＰＯＧってわけかよ！
Are you a POG member to the core now?!
また「愚者のパズル」なんて
作りやがって！
You built a Fools' Puzzle again!
愚者のパズル？　違うな。
こいつは　てめえを→
A Fools' Puzzle? Wrong.
This puzzle was built for the sole purpose of throwing you to your death.
奈落に突き落とすために作った
死のパズルだ！
It's a Puzzle of Death!
うっ。
３本　落とすぜ！
I'm dropping three more!
パズルに人殺しは　させねえ！
絶対にだ！
I won't let you use puzzles for murder! Never!
へっ。　自分の命が　やべえってのに
相変わらず　甘えなあ！
You're still fussing about that when your life's on the line?
さあ　命がけのパズルタイムを
楽しもうぜ！　アインシュタイン！
Let's enjoy this puzzle time of life and death, Einstein!
kimi no nounai he shinnyuu nemutteiru sukima ni
I infiltrate your brain while you're sleeping.
Baby, open the gate!
fukuzatsu sugi sekyuriti kakusareru to abakitaku naru
The security's too tough, but I want to expose what's hidden.
barabara ni chirabatteiru pasuwado wo hiroi atsume
I gather the pieces of the shattered password.
kakushin ni sematte iku sono shoutai wo misete
I get close to the core. Show me who you really are!
kantan ni kuria dekinai saki nante motto yomenai
I can't clear it easily. I can't even see what lies ahead.
kaidoku fukanou sumairu kikenna pazuru
Your indecipherable smile is a hazardous puzzle.
rokku sareta doa aru nara zutto tataite miru beki kazana hiraku wa
When you see a locked door, you should just hit it until a crack opens.
eien ni hodokenai nazo nanka wa nai
There's no mystery that lasts forever!
makiokosu, it's a supernova
I made it, it's a supernova!
tobikiri shigekitekina hirameki wo agemashou
Let's flash so bright it'd hurt!
Misskey-Misskey La-Tu-Ma
yume no naka it's a supernova
In my dreams, it's a supernova!
watashi wa sou brain diver
Yeah, I'm the brain diver!
kimi ga sagashi motometeru kotae ni nareru made
Until I can find the answer you're looking for...
Brain diver!
Accelerating Challenge
（ミハル）あっ…　おいしい…
おいしいです！
This... This is really good!
（ノノハ）いっぱいあるから
どんどん　お代わりしてね。
There's plenty, so have as much as you'd like.
うわっ。
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
こんなにおいしい晩御飯が
いただけるのは→
The only reason I can have such a wonderful dinner
あの時　ノノハさんが
声をかけてくれたおかげです。
is because you were kind enough to say hi to me back then!
う～っ。
ありがとうございます　ノノハさん！
Thank you so much, Nonoha! You saved my life!
ノノハさんは　命の恩人です！
捨てるお兄ちゃん　あれば
拾うノノハさん　ありです！
You took me in when my brother threw me away!
ミハルちゃんのこと　捨てたわけじゃ
ないと思うよ　ギャモン君は…。
I don't think Gammon threw you away...
ギャモン君…。
心の声
Gammon...
回想
（エレナ）ルーク様が誘ったの。　ただし
オファーを受諾したのは　ガリレオ自身。
Rook invited him.
But Galileo accepted the offer.
ギャモン君がＰＯＧに…。
心の声
Gammon is in the POG now...
（おなかの鳴る音）
ああ。
ほら　食べて　食べて。
Come on, eat up, eat up!
今日は泊まっていって　いいから！
あ　ありがとうございます！
You can stay over tonight.
Thank you so much!
あっ。
いい食べっぷり！
You're a good eater! You even eat the onions!
ネギも残さず　食べてるし！
私　ネギ　大好きなんです！
I love onions!
腕に　よりをかけた
かいがあったわ！
It was worth the effort I put into making it then.
あっ。　それにしても…→
But still...
こんな時間まで　どこ　ほっつき
歩いてんだか？　あのネギ嫌いは。
What could that onion-hater be doing this late?
To Kaito,
Dinner with Miharu!
Come on over
if you come home!
Nonoha
I'm dropping one.
１本落とす！
へっ　俺は３本だ。
And I'm dropping three.
（ダイスマン）ガチで押してるっすよ。
ガリレオのやつ。
Galileo's pushing him hard.
（メイズ）しかし　よくも　まあ
こんなパズルを思いつくわね。→
But considering the puzzle he thought up, he's not bad.
取れる鉄骨は　一度に３本まで。
You can take three beams at once.
最終的に　相手の乗っている鉄骨を
落とした方が勝ち。
In the end, you win if you can drop the beam your opponent is on.
立体になった陣取り合戦って事で
いいんですかね？
So it's like a three-dimensional capture-the-base game, right?
（フンガ）
それほど単純なものではない。
（メイズ・ダイスマン）うっ？！
It's not so simple.
（フンガ）パズル本体と接していない
鉄骨は　すべて地面に落ちる。
Every beam not connected to the puzzle falls.
つまり　取り方しだいでは　一度に
何本もの鉄骨を落とすことが→
Which means that depending on the way you choose them,
you can make multiple beams fall at the same time.
可能ということだ。
立体であるがゆえに　解き方
そして攻め方が無数に存在する…。
Because it's three-dimensional,
the number of solutions and methods of attack is close to infinite.
これは　恐ろしく高度な
対戦パズルだ！
This is a fearsome, high-level duel puzzle!
My time to think is limited to one minute too.
しかも　１分しか考える時間は
ねえと　きたもんだ。
It pisses me off, but it's an interesting puzzle.
むかつくけど
おもしれえパズルだぜ！
（爆発音と鉄骨が落下する音）
だから　なおさら　むかつく！
And it pisses me off even more that you want to use it for murder!
これが　人殺しのパズルだって
ことがな！
Do you even understand what you're doing?!
何やってるか
分かってんのかよ？！
金になんか　つられて
恥ずかしくねえのか！
Aren't you ashamed to go this far for money?
金？　まだ　そんなこと
言ってんのか　てめえは。
Money? Are you still going on about that?
金なんて　もう　どうでもいい！
Who cares about money! I'm aiming for something far greater than that!
俺は　もっと　すげえもん
狙ってんだ！
あっ？！
俺は　神のパズルを解き→
I'll solve the Divine Puzzle and get the ultimate treasure, the Divine Revelations!
究極の財　「神の書」を
手に入れてやる！
Gammon! Don't tell me you joined the POG for that?!
ギャモン　まさか　そんなもんのために
ＰＯＧに？！
手にした者に　全能の力を
与えるっつう　とんでもねえ財→
A crazy treasure that makes you omnipotent.
The Divine Revelations.
「神の書」。　それを封じてるのは→
It's sealed in the Divine Puzzle that no one has ever solved.
いまだ誰も解くことができてねえ
「神のパズル」だ。
ギヴァーも　ソルヴァーも
魅了されねえやつは　いねえ。
There's not a Solver or Giver who wouldn't be mesmerized by that!
使えよ　カイト…　腕輪の力を！
なにっ？！
Use the power of the Armband, Kaito!
What?
I'll show you that you can't defeat me even if you do use it!
そいつを使っても　てめえは
俺に勝てねえってことを→
この戦いで　はっきりさせてやる。
そして…。
And then...
俺が　ファイ・ブレインだってことを
証明してやるぜ！
I'll prove that I am the Phi Brain!
へっ　冗談！　べ～！
Yeah, right!
俺は　てめえなんかに
絶対　負けねえ！
I'll never lose to you!
へっ！　どうした？
What's wrong? Is that all you can do without the Armband?
腕輪を使わねえと　こんなもんか？
へっ！　ほざいてろ！
Cut the crap!
腕輪なんか無くてもなぁ
こんなパズル　楽勝なんだよ！
Even without the Armband, a puzzle like this is easy as pie!
I can see it. If I drop those two beams...
心の声
見えた。　あの鉄骨を２本取れば…。
こ　これは？！
Th-This...
Kaito! Do you have the time to be spacing out?
カイト！
あっ。
何　ボケッとしてやがる。
とっとと　取りやがれ！
Drop them already!
うっ　うるせい！
Shut up!
What was that just now?
心の声
何だったんだ？　今のは…。
間違いない。　あの鉄骨を
２本取れば　俺の勝ち。
If I drop those two beams, I'll definitely win.
だが…。
心の声
But...
ああなっちまうってのか…。
Will he end up like that?
もうすぐ時間切れだぜ　大門カイト！
Your time's almost up, Daimon Kaito!
Dammit, I know that! I'm dropping that one!
くそっ！　分かってらぁ！
この１本を取る！
デハハハハッ！
下手こきやがったな　アインシュタイン！
You made your final mistake, Einstein!
見えたぜ　てめえの最期が！
うっ。
１つ！
（爆発音）
One!
Two!
２つ。
（爆発音）
ははっ。
これで　とどめだ！
It's over!
あっ！
うっ！
（ビショップ）「そこまでです」。
Stop right there!
（ビショップ）ルーク様のご命令です。
ここは　ひきなさい。　ガリレオのギャモン！
Sir Rook has ordered you to retreat, Gammon the Galileo!
What?! Don't screw with me! One move and he's gone!
いや～？！　ふざけんじゃねえぞ！
この一手で　こいつを！
As a member of the POG, Sir Rook's orders are absolute.
ＰＯＧの一員である以上
ルーク様のご命令は絶対です。
ルーク…。
ケッ！　チェ！
Rook...
命拾いしたな　アインシュタイン！
You escaped death, Einstein!
んん…　お兄ちゃん…　ネギ…。
Gammon... Onions...
すっげ～！　君　マジ　すげえよ！
Amazing! You're fucking amazing, man!
まさか　大門カイトを　あそこまで
追い詰めるなんてね。
You backed Daimon Kaito into a corner like it was nothing!
まあ　僕は　すげえやつだとは
最初から思ってたけどね。
Well, I knew there was something special
about you from the beginning, my main man Gammon.
ギャモンちゃんのこと。
ふっ…。
いや　まずい茶だぜ。
おい！　淹れ方がなってねえぞ！
This tea sucks.
Learn how to make tea, dammit.
悪うございましたね。
淹れなれてないもので…。
Forgive my incompetence.
I'm inexperienced with making tea.
こんなやつが　幹部待遇って
ありえないんだけど。
How can we have a guy like this in the leadership?
He's shown results. We have no choice but to accept.
結果を出した。
納得せざるをえまい。
俺は納得いかねえがな。　大門カイトを
殺せと言ったのは　ルークだ。
I can't accept it though.
Rook told me to kill Daimon Kaito.
なぜ　止めた？
計画の一環です。
Why did you stop me?
It is one step in the plan.
あなたが　ＰＯＧの一員として
信頼できると分かれば→
We needed to be sure we could trust you.
いずれ　詳細を。
ふん…　そうかよ。
だが　次のパズルは　そうは　いかねえ。
Oh, really. But you can't do that with the next puzzle!
あんたらが　止める間もなく
やつを地獄に送ってやるぜ。
I'll throw him down to Hell so quick you won't have time to stop me.
（ビショップ）予想以上の働きでした。
Sakanoue Gammon did better than expected.
逆之上ギャモン…ルーク様が止めなければ
大門カイトは　あのまま…。
Had you not stopped him, Daimon Kaito would have...
本当に大門カイトを倒したその時は
彼がファイ・ブレインに？
Would he really become a Phi Brain if he defeated Daimon Kaito?
あれを。
Look.
（ビショップ）オルペウスの腕輪が　今までとは
違う反応をしている。
The Armband of Orpheus is acting different than usual.
（ルーク）カイトの脳が　急速に
活性化している証拠だ。
That proves that Kaito's brain is rapidly activating.
Do you mean the Armband was active?
腕輪が発動していたと
いうことですか？
あれは　無意識に　腕輪の力を
引き出しているときの反応だ。
That is the sign of a subconscious activation.
ファイ・ブレインとしての完成も近い。
He is close to a complete Phi Brain.
ですが　気になることが　１つ。
However, something is bothering me.
腕輪が発動していたとすれば→
I have a hard time believing
大門カイトが　簡単に負けるとは
思えません。
he would have lost so easily with the Armband active.
もしや…　勝てなかった。　もしくは
勝とうとしなかった理由が→
Is there a reason why he couldn't win,
or did he even try to win in the first place?
あるとか？
（ルーク）さあね。→
Who knows?
分かっているのは　カイトが　確実に
成長しているということだ。
All we know for certain is that Kaito is progressing.
Sakanoue Gammon... He'll become a very important piece in the puzzle.
逆之上ギャモン…
彼は　最強のピースになるだろう。
カイトの次なる扉を開くための…。
For Kaito to open the next gate...
では　逆之上ギャモンの監視を
継続します。
In that case, I shall continue surveillance on Sakanoue Gammon.
彼が　本当にＰＯＧに恭順したのか
確信できるまでは。
Until we can be sure of his allegiance to the POG.
Right.
カイトは加速を始めた。
Kaito has started accelerating.
もはや　君にも
止めることはできない。
Not even you can stop him now.
カイト！
カイト　きのう　どこ行ってたの？
Kaito!
Kaito, where were you yesterday?
書き置きしておいたでしょう？
晩御飯できてるって。
I left you a note inviting you over for dinner!
見てねえよ。
もう！　ミハルちゃんと待ってたのに。
I didn't see it.
Come on! Miharu and I were waiting!
はぁ～！　ミハルちゃんって
ホント　かわいい！
Miharu's so cute, you know!
ギャモン君の妹だなんて
信じられないよね！
I can't believe she's Gammon's sister!
ギャモン君が帰ってくるまで
ずっと　うちに住まないかな？
I wonder if she'll stay at my place until Gammon comes back.
ん？　どうしたの？　カイト。
どうもしねえよ。
What's wrong, Kaito?
Nothing.
（ソウジ）いや～！
朝から　仲のよろしいことで。
I see you're getting along well this morning.
ん？！　軸川先輩。
Jikugawa!
だけど　よろしくない情報が
１つあるんだよね。
But I have some bad news for you.
カイト君　きのう　ＰＯＧと
パズルで戦ったんだってね。
Kaito, I hear you fought the POG in a puzzle yesterday.
えっ？！
ギヴァーは　逆之上ギャモン。
The Giver was Sakanoue Gammon.
あっ？！
ビックリしたよ。
I was surprised. I didn't think he'd go along with Chief Crossfield.
彼が　クロスフィールド管理官に
付くことになるとはね。
どうりで　学校にも
来てないはずだ。
He isn't even coming to school anymore.
じゃあ　カイトが　ゆうべ
居なかったのって。
So that's where you were last night...
そう。　ギャモン君のパズルに挑戦し…
負けた。
Yes. He challenged Gammon's puzzle...
and lost.
はい？！
Come again?
（武田・相沢）なに～っ？！
What?!
（武田）僕たちが倒す前に　誰に
負けたというのだ？　大門カイト君！
You lost to someone before we could defeat you, Daimon Kaito?!
（相沢）そうだ！　お前を倒すのは
負けるたびに改良し→
Yeah! Takeda's sudoku improves and revives as a zombie
ゾンビのごとく
よみがえってきた～→
every single time you defeat it! It's what's destined to defeat you!
この武田ナンプレだと決まってる！
そのとおり！
Exactly!
（アイリ）また　瞬殺される姿が
目に浮かぶみたいです。
I bet you two would be beaten in a second again.
ふ～。
ふん。　おい！　逃げるのか！
Hey, are you running away?!
あっ　カイト！　待ちなさい！
ふっ　逃げた　だと！
Wait, Kaito!
He ran away?!
やりましたね　武田さん！
戦わずして勝ったんですよ！
We did it, Takeda!
We won without even fighting!
なに？！
What?!
To think this day would finally come!
まさか　こんな日が来るとは！
武田さん！
くう～っ！
Takeda!
ナオキ！
ユウイチ！
Naoki!
Yuuichi!
無視されただけじゃないですか？
（２人）なに～っ？！
Didn't he just ignore you?
What?!
（エレナ）あらあら。
なじんじゃってますこと。
I see you're making yourself at home.
（エレナ）やっぱ　違和感ありまくり。
あんたが　ＰＯＧにいるなんて。
It feels so weird to have you at the POG.
ヘッ。　グダグダしてたもんが
吹っ切れて　すっきりしたけどな。
I feel refreshed from getting rid of what I complained about.
その「神のパズル」ってののためにね。
ふ～ん。
And it's all for the Divine Puzzle, huh?
Is that really your true intention?
それ　ホントに　あんたの本音？
あん？
Huh?
なんか　私の知ってるあんたと
違うっぽいのよね。
It's different from what the Gammon I know would do.
パズルの作り方　解き方を見れば→
If you watch someone make and solve puzzles,
相手が　どんな人間なのかは
分かるもん。
ほう…。
you can understand what kind of a person they are.
You're kind and easily moved, in sharp contrast to what you try to show.
あんたって　顔に似合わず
情にもろくて　お人よし。
パズルでつながった人を
財と同じくらいに大切に思ってる。
If you connect with people through puzzles,
you treasure them just as much as the treasure itself.
実力を認める大門カイト…
彼のことは　特にね。
You acknowledge others' prowess... Especially Daimon Kaito's.
彼を殺そうとしたのだって　彼なら
なんとかするって信じてたから。
You tried to kill him because you believed he'd do something about it.
ふん。
大切な友達を裏切ってまで→
You must have a reason for betraying your dear friends and joining the POG.
ＰＯＧに入る理由が　あんたには
あった…。　そうなんでしょ？
Am I right?
やれやれ。　そこまで
お見通しだったとはな。
I didn't think you'd see through me so easily.
うふっ。　やっぱり…。
I thought so.
...is what you wanted me to say?
…とでも言ってほしかったのか？
えっ？！
生き馬の目を抜く芸能界を
渡ってきた割にゃあ→
You came from the cutthroat world of entertainment business,
その目は　節穴みたいだなあ。
姫川エレナ！
yet you're blind as a bat, Himekawa Elena.
あんなネギも食えねえやつが
友達とか…→
That onion-hater freak is my friend?
ペラい事　ほざいてんじゃねえよ。
ネギって…。
Don't yak about stuff you're clueless about.
Onion what?
大門カイト。　やつは踏み台だ。
俺が　神のパズルを解くためのな。
Daimon Kaito is just a stepping stone for me to solve the Divine Puzzle.
カイトもルークも　全員ぶっ倒し
俺がファイ・ブレインになる。
I'll defeat Kaito, Rook, and all you freaks. Then I'll become the Phi Brain.
それができるのは　ギヴァーとソルヴァー
両方の力を持つ俺様だけだ。
That's only possible for me, who's a Giver and Solver in one.
証明してやるぜ。
I'll show you.
I'll solve the ultimate puzzle and prove that I'm the ultimate being.
究極のパズルを解いて　俺様が
究極の存在だってことをな。
あっ　あっ！
ふん。
Is that who you really are?
それが　あんたの本音なんだ？
はっ。
変わっちゃったんだね　ホントに…。
You've really changed.
あんたの　その笑い方
好きだったんだけどなぁ。
I liked the way you laughed.
はいはい　トンチンカンなこと言って
すみませんでしたね。
Sorry for being off the mark.
じゃあ　今後とも
頑張ってくださいな。　地堂　刹センセ。
Keep up the good work, Master Chido Setsu.
はっ　もう　信じらんない！
アイドルの顔面　つかむなんて！
I can't believe this.
How dare he pinch the face of an idol!
あっ　あっ　あっ。
アメンボ　赤いな　ぽろぽろり～ん！
Now it's lovely red like an apple.
ぴろぴろり～ん！
なんで黙ってたのよ。
ギャモン君と戦ったこと。
Why didn't you tell me that you fought Gammon?
いいから　そこ押さえてろ。
何　それ？　ギャモン君に負けたくせに。
Just leave it at that.
Come on, you lost to him.
負けてねえ！
I didn't lose.
はぁ…　信じたくなかったなぁ。
ギャモン君がＰＯＧに行ったこと…。
I didn't want to believe that he joined the POG.
みんなが居ないと
こんなに広かったんだ。
This terrace seems so big now that no one else is here.
このテラスって…。
ギャモン君は　ＰＯＧに行っちゃって
キューちゃんもアナも　バラバラ…。
Gammon joined the POG...
Cubie and Ana are in pieces...
なんで　こんなことに
なっちゃったんだろう。
Why did it have to come to this?
心の声
なんで　あんなものを見たんだ。
Why did I see that?
これを取れば　勝てる。
心の声
その答えが見えた瞬間に→
The moment I saw that I would win if I took out those two beams...
あのとき
心の声
俺が勝っていれば　世界は？
If I won at that moment, the world would...
Oh well, you managed to make even me gloomy!
な～んて　私まで暗くなっても
しかたないよね。
だったら…。
心の声
ん？！　カイト？
Kaito?
だったら　俺が見た景色
心の声
あれは…。
Then the scenery I saw back then is...
未来？！
カ　カイト？！
...the future?
Kaito?
Why are you eating onions?
なんで…　ネギ食べてるの？
（真方ジン）こんな事になるとは…。
あっ？！
To think it had to end like this...
ジ　ジン？！
Jin!
どうなってんだ？！
What's going on here?
（真方ジン）やはり「神の書」は　人が
手にすべきものではなかった。
The Divine Revelations is not meant for mortals.
ピタゴラスが封じたあの力は…
人には過ぎたものだったのだ。
The power that Pythagoras sealed was too much for humans.
これが　神のパズルを解き
全能の力を手にした人類の末路→
This is the end of humankind after they acquired divine powers.
世界の最期か？
Is this the end of the world?
Are you telling me this will happen if the Divine Puzzle is released?
まさか　神のパズルが解放されたら
こうなるっていうのか？
今　俺が見ているものが
未来だっていうのか！
Are you telling me I'm seeing the future?
Is this the world you wanted, Phi Brain?
これが　お前の望んだ世界なのか…
ファイ・ブレイン！
教えてくれ　ジン！　ジン！　ジ～ン！
Tell me, Jin! Jin!
Jin!
（パズルを壊す音）
カイト！
はぁ？！
Kaito!
どうしちゃったの？
顔　真っ青だよ。
What's wrong?
You're as pale as a ghost.
カイト？！
ここから先は…　やべえ。
Kaito?
This path leads to...
Dammit.
あっ　カイト！　ちょっと！
Hey, Kaito!
Hey!
あ～！　痛～っ！
Ow!
こっ　小指！　カイト！　小指打った！
My toe... Kaitoe! I hit my toe!
痛っ！　カイト～！
Ouch! Kaito!
The Divine Puzzle, huh?
神のパズル…　か。
（ビショップ）ここは冷えますよ。
It will be cold soon.
これを…。　ＰＯＧ幹部の証しです。
Put this on.
It's the uniform of a POG leader.
あなたの意志　決意　覚悟…
見せていただきました。
We have seen your will, resolve, and determination.
私たちに力を貸していただきたい。
神のパズルの解放　そのために…。
We want you to help us.
To release the Divine Puzzle...
Yeah.
あれが　未来…。
That's the future...
ＰＯＧが…
神の書を手に入れたやつが→
If the POG... or whoever solves the Divine Puzzle
あんな世界を創るってんなら
解かせるわけにはいかねえ。
will create a world like that, I can't let them solve it!
神のパズルは　俺が解く！
I'll solve the Divine Puzzle!
No mortal must ever reach the Divine Revelations.
（バロン）「神の書」は
人が手にしてはならない。
世界と　そして
未来を守るためにも。
For the sake of the world and the future.
そうでしょう…　ジン。
Right, Jin?
tsukue no ue de umareta sekai
This world born on my table.
ichiban saki ni kimi ni misetakatta
I wanted you to see it first.
karappo no heya sotto nukedashite hashiri hajimeteta
I sneaked out of the empty room and started to run.
iki hazamasete oka wo noboru to
As I got to the top of the hill, out of breath,
kimi ga saki ni tsuite matteita ne
you were already there waiting for me.
takusan no hajimete kimi to mitsuketa takaramono datta
It was the first of many treasures we would find together.
kanashisa de afureta toki wa
When sorrow was overflowing in me,
nanimo iwazu ni tada soba ni ite kureta ne
you just silently stayed by my side.
ima de mo wasurenai yo
I still haven't forgotten that.
mata aou ne yakusoku wo shiyou
Let's promise we'll meet again.
kie wa shinai ano hi no sayonara
The goodbye of that day we'll never forget.
boku no subete kimi ga kureta michi
All I have I got from you,
zutto kokoro no naka hikaru yo
and it will all shine in my heart forever.